Okay, so in this video, I
just want to briefly talk about
organizational change management
and just a couple of theories
involved in organizational
change management.
Now, this section, organizational change
management, is very different to change
control that we've been talking about,
right?
And the integrated change control process,
that was part of integration management.
Right.
So change control is about the project.
We need to properly control all of the
changes on our project.
So somebody's identified the need for a
change.
We have to do an impact analysis and so on
and so forth.
This is not what this is talking about.
Here, we're talking about organizational
change management.
So change within the entire organization
as a whole.
So really, really, really this falls under
business environment domain, right?
So it's talking about the organization as
a whole, right?
So changes that are made within the
organization.
And so really it's part of conflict.
I mean, we can talk about this as part of
a conflict, right, because they understand
something important, and that is generally
people resist change.
And it depends on the organization
obviously.
but as a general rule, people are going to
resist change, and therefore it can be a
source of conflict, especially in an
organization where the average tenure is,
say, 20 years.
The average tenure of
their employees is 20 years,
and now you want to
institute a big, huge change.
There's going to be resistance there.
So, if there are any organizational changes,
they need to be properly controlled.
Right?
So rather than making one big,
huge, large change to the organisation,
I mean, whatever it is,
you know, I mean, we can
potentially even change the
culture of the organisation.
A lot of times it's better to make small
incremental changes.
Right.
There's a simple example going from a
private company to a public company.
That's a huge, huge change to your
organisation.
Employees are going to resist that,
right?
Because they're going to say, oh,
a lot of the benefits.
I have, they might be going away,
so, you know, so, you know, everything is
about the shareholder and so on and so
forth.
So people generally resist change, right,
when it comes to
organizational change, right?
So it needs to be properly controlled.
Now, there are two basic theories that you
just need to be aware of.
There's something very new that's been
added to the exam.
One of them is this one called the Lewin
McKinsey 7S model and the 7S and then
stands for strategy structure systems
shared values style staff and skills and
again you don't need to know these in any
amount of detail right just be aware that
this is one of the models right one of the
change management theory models right
Lewin McKinsey seven seven
S model right so strategy plan
for building and maintaining
a competitive advantage.
Why are we doing this change?
What is the purpose of this change?
The structure, how is a company organized?
So that can determine, you know,
how we're going to implement the change.
Also, what kind of systems are there,
daily activities that staff use to do
their work or daily tools that staff used
to do their work.
And then some of the shared values of the
organization, right, the core values,
culture, work ethics and so and so forth.
Again, how is that going to impact how we
will implement the change?
In some organisation, especially small
start-up companies, for example,
startup companies are always changing.
It's constantly, constantly changing.
So employees in a startup company,
they're expecting change.
So their whole culture is about change.
Whereas a company that's been around for
many, many decades, right?
And like I said, the
average tenure is 20 years,
then they're going to resist major change.
That is going to impact how an
organization is going to handle a major
change like that, I made a change to the
organization.
And then styles of leadership,
right, and then the employees themselves.
So, you know, the demeanor and the
acceptance or non-acceptance of employees.
So staff, skill sets, and so and so forth.
Now that's one theory.
Another theory is something called Cotter
Theory, right?
And this is an eight-step theory.
And again, just be aware of it.
You don't need to know any huge amount of
detail.
So the eight-steps end, create a sense of
urgency, build a guiding coalition,
form a strategic vision, enlist a
volunteer army, enable action by removing
barriers, generate short-term wins,
sustain acceleration, institute change.
Again, you don't need to know these in any
detail.
Just know that These are the basic steps.